Guide to the Margaret G. Reid Papers 1904-1990
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Research and Writings
  - Subseries 3: Income and Health
    - Homicide and accidental death, data, undated (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
    - Household membership, draft and data, circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Household production and health, notes, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Human capital and poverty, research materials, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Income and benefits, data and research materials, 1970-1982 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Income and child health, notes, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Income and disability, data, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Income and health, drafts and data, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 40, Folder 1-8)
    - Income, health, and disability, data, circa 1970s (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Income, Health, and Disability," drafts, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 2-9)
    - "Income, Health, and Disability," drafts and data, 1970s (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Income, Health, and Disability," drafts and data, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "Income, Health, and Labour Force," draft, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 3-4)
    - Income and race, data, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - "Income, Schooling, and Health," draft, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Income, veterans, data, 1960, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - "Labour Force, Participation, and Health," drafts and data, circa 1974-1977 (Box 43, Folder 1-6)
    - "Measures of Health and Populations Compared," draft, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Medical care expenditures, data, 1950-1960 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Medical Care Project, correspondence, 1950 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - "Mortality, Income, and Schooling," draft, circa 1970s (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Mortality rates and income, draft and data, circa 1970s (Box 43, Folder 11-12)
    - New Palgrave Dictionary, correspondence, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Race and education, data, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Race and medical care, data and notes, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Smoking, effects, drafts and data, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Stock of Health of Persons of Age Groups by Demographic Characteristics," drafts and data, circa 1970s (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - University of Chicago Economics Department, faculty list, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Veterans, data, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - White males, data, 1970s, undated (Box 44, Folder 8-9)
  - Subseries 4: General
    - Bibliography, 1978 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Computations, 1978, undated (Box 45, Folder 2-4)
    - Computer cards, 1960, 1977, undated (Box 45, Folder 5-7)
    - CV and list of publications, 1981, undated (Box 45, Folder 8-9)
    - Data, 1960-1977 (Box 45, Folder 10-16)
    - Data, 1960-1977, undated (Box 46, Folder 1-7)
    - Data, demographic, 1978, undated (Box 46, Folder 8-9)
    - Data, state review, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Notes, undated (Box 46, Folder 11-13)
    - Research notes, index cards, undated (Box 47)
    - Bibliographies, index cards, undated (Box 48)
    - Bibliographies, index cards, and computer cards, undated (Box 49)
    - Bibliographies, index cards, and computer cards, undated (Box 50)
  - Subseries 5: Writings by Others
    - American Statistical Association Journal, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - American Statistical Association Journal, book reviews, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Baker, Georgianne, "Household Production: A Cultural and Cross-National View," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Beutler, Ivan, and Alma Owen, "New Perspectives on Production in the Home," undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Consumers and consumption, articles, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Damus, Sylvester, "A Two Part Ramsey-Optimum Railroad Tariff," dissertation abstract, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Davis, Joseph, "Standards and Content of Living," 1945 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Firebaugh, Francille, and Ruth Deacon, "The Contribution of Women to Development of the Family and the Economy," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Government Revenue and Inflation," table of contents, undated (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Hartley, Peter R., "Two Essays on Rational Expectations," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Heckman, James, "Longitudinal Studies in Labour Economics," 1980 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Hill, T.P., "Do-it-yourself and the GDP," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Hogan, Janice, "Household Production in Contemporary Lifestyles," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Household economics, articles, 1930s-1940s (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Modigliani, Franco, and Richard Brumberg, "Utility Analysis and the Consumption Function," undated (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Murphy, Martin, "The Measurement and Valuation of Non-market Economic Activities," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Mushkin, Selma, "Why Health Economics?" undated (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Nickell, Stephen, "Unemployment and the Structure of Labour Costs," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Otsuka, Keijiro, and Yujiro Hayami, "Theories of Share Tenancy: A Critical Survey," 1985 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Phipard, Esther, and Hazel Stiebeling, "Adequacy of American Diets," 1949 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Productivity and rural sociology, articles, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Projector, Dorothy S., "Survey of Changes in Family Finances," 1968 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Reynolds, Roger, "The Joint Determination of Health and Income," with correspondence, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Rosen, Sherwin, "Some Socio-economic determinants of mortality," 1980 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Schultz, Paul, "Individual and Per Capita Family Income Inequality," 1981 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Sharkey, William Walker, "A Study of Markets Involving Increasing Returns and Uncertain Demand," dissertation abstract, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Staab, Josephine, "The Effect of Classification on the Coefficient of Income Elasticity of Farm Family Expenditures," 1955 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Stafford, Frank, "The Use of Time and Technology by Households in the U.S.," 1981 (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Wages and income, book reviews, 1954 (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - Walker, Kathryn, "Time Measurement and the Value of Nonmarket Household Production," 1979 (Box 51, Folder 30)
- Series II: Personal
  This series is divided into two subseries:
  Subseries 1: Papers, contains address books, bills, cards, certificates, clippings, personal correspondence, prints, a passport, and a journal. Of note is the journal, which details faculty politics at Iowa State College circa 1943. Oversized certificates have been moved to Series III. Material spans 1933-1986.
  Subseries 2: Photographs, contains photographs of Reid's friends and family from 1904-1990.
  - Subseries 1: Papers
    - Address book and record book, 1988-1990, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - American Economic Association, Distinguished Fellow Award and correspondence, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Asian prints, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Bills, 1982-1984 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Bowman, Mary Jean, Columbia University Teacher's College Medal, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - British passport, 1933 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Canadian Federation of University Women, The Chronicle, 1960-1961 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Check, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Christmas and birthday cards, 1980s, undated (Box 52, Folder 9-12)
    - Clippings, 1982, undated (Box 52, Folder 13-14)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Gettysburg Address and Bill of Rights, copies, undated (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Journal, circa 1943 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Knight, Frank, memorial speech and papers, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Legends of the North Carolina Coast, Pocahontas Wight Edmunds, with postcards, 1941 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Musical recordings, list, undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - USPS postage rates, list, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - University of Chicago, faculty card and library card, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - University of Chicago, University of Manitoba, and other universities, diplomas, 1918-1982 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Van Gogh print, undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Who's Who, correspondence, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2: Photographs
    - Angus, Bonnie, and Anne, circa 1950s (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Back garden, undated (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Cabin in the snow, undated (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Camping with the cats, undated (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Christmas, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Doris, undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Family, undated (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Family farmhouse, John Reid, undated (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Family and friends, undated (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Gail gets called to the Ontario Bar, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Gerry, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Jack, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Margaret (Jr) with Jordan and Grahame, 1984-1986 (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - The McDonalds, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - McFetridge, Peter Reid as a baby, undated (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - McFetridge, Peter Reid marrying Jean, undated (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - Norway, friends or family, 1982-1983 (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - Patricia, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - Patricia and Ben's wedding, undated, and with their children, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - Plum, David, 1939 (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - Reid, John, and Sarah Clements, 1904 (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - Reid, Margaret, undated (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - Reid, Margaret, and Jack, 1954 (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - Reid, Margaret, and Jack in Vancouver, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - Reid, Margaret, and Jack at Beaconhill Lodge, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 35)
    - Tree, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 36)
    - Trinity Lodge, undated (Box 53, Folder 37)
    - Unidentified children, undated (Box 53, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified couple, 1957 (Box 53, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified gatherings, undated (Box 53, Folder 40)
    - Unidentified man with President Reagan, undated (Box 53, Folder 41)
    - Unidentified people, 1948-1961 (Box 53, Folder 42)
    - Unidentified people, undated (Box 53, Folder 43-44)
    - Van Haute, Stephanie, undated (Box 53, Folder 45)
    - Van Haute, Stephanie with David and Gillian, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 46)
    - Wilcox, Bob and Margaret, 1942 (Box 53, Folder 47)
- Series III: Oversize
  This series contains clippings, certificates, and research data. It includes a copy of Reid's book Consumers and the Market. Newspaper clippings are in poor condition. They relate to controversies at the University of Illinois during Howard Bowen's tenure as Dean of the College of Commerce and Business Administration. Bowen was forced to resign in 1950 and his departure was followed by a wave of resignations by economics faculty. A copy of resignation letter written by chair Everett E. Hagen can be found in Series I, Subseries 1, under "University of Illinois." This series covers 1938-1977.
  - Alphabetical file, blank, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Computations, circa 1975 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Data, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Data, 1965-1974 (Box 54, Folder 4-5)
  - Data, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Family expenditure and consumption, data, 1950-1970 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Farm data, circa 1940s (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - University of Manitoba, Honourary Doctor of Laws, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Who's Who of Intellectuals, Certificate of Inclusion, 1977 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Champaign-Urbana Courier and University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign student newspapers, clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 55, Folder 1-4)
  - Reid, Consumers and the Market, 1938 (Box 55, Folder 5)